They say God has left us.
Couldn't believe
what we've become.
I think this to be true.
Matty, baby.
I'm so sorry.
...given us pause
to reflect on what we've lost.
- Our world used
to vibrate with life,
but now it's...
...it's just eerily quiet.
It's nearly four years
since the outbreak,
and the days are definitely
getting longer and harder.
Feels like we're stuck
on a hamster wheel
and can't get off.
Howlers have ravaged the hills
and killed off
most of the animals we hunt.
GMA officials continue to track
in the mountains,
capturing, or should I say,
murdering, many of us runners.
But there are stories
surfacing about
riots breaking out in the camps.
Finally, people
are starting to fight back
against the regime.
We've buried too many out here,
made too many makeshift graves
for friends, family,
people just trying to survive.
But we cling to better days,
use them as--
Coming today, kiddo?
Is it okay if I skip?
I just need a walk.
Not too far.
You hear?
I heard you.
Hyah! Hyah!
Hyah!
Did you get it, brother?
I got it.
- You ain't got bit, did you?
- Agents clipped me.
- Fuck. Fuck.
- They're on my arse.
Get on.
- You gotta go.
- No way.
-We're both getting out of here.
-Yeah, I can hold 'em off.
I'm not fucking leaving
without you.
I'm not the one
that needs saving, mate.
Give me your hat.
Fuck.
Don't worry, mate.
Looks better on me anyway.
Go. Go!
Hyah! Hyah!
Get down!
Cover me!
Aah!
Fuck.
Fuck!
- He talking?
- Not to me.
The other one?
- Tracks lead north.
- He has it?
He has to, and he's injured.
Brooks shot him leaving camp.
Well, at least
someone's doing their job.
You know, you runners
are the bane of my existence,
and yet...
...you don't actually
make a difference.
You're just
a fuckin' nuisance, really.
And look at the state of you.
For what?
And yet...
I'd still rather
be a runner...
...than a sell-out
in one of your prison camps.
Would you?
Where's he going?
Fuck you.
Mm.
Fuck me?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Should have been
taken back to camp.
Processed properly.
He was never gonna talk,
and the camps are full.
-Come on,
let's get the other one.
-We need another team.
There are none. All the agents
are taken up with the riots.
And what if he's going
for the forest?
Wounded?
If we push on,
it'll get close to dark.
Well, you better
track him quick, then.
Let's go.
Hey. Easy.
What are you doing
out here alone?
Shh.
Hey.
Hey, kiddo.
How was the walk?
Yeah, fine.
Only got two today.
Who'd have thought
we'd run out of these mongrels?
I, uh...
I found another runner up there.
Henry somebody.
Eaten to the bone.
Hopefully not
ol' Henry Lawrence.
Remember?
He was a grumpy old bugger.
I, uh...
I saw some GMA agents
down at the river.
So we're gonna have
to lay low for a few days.
No more walks.
I need to show you
something, Otto.
Who the hell's this?
I found him barely conscious.
Where?
Rory, where?
At the river.
I don't want you
near that river.
-You'll be torn to pieces.
-I know.
- Is he infected?
-  -He's not showing symptoms.
He's been shot.
Is this bloke GMA?
I don't know.
He was carrying this.
What were
you thinking?
-I thought we could--
-We could what?
Help him.
Those agents,
they'll be looking for him.
Right? You could have
led 'em straight here.
What was I supposed to do?
Just leave him to die?
That's exactly what
you're supposed to do!
-What are we gonna do?
-Well, it's too late
to move him now.
First light...
...he's off our property.
-Where are you going?
-To board up.
There's a storm coming.
They'll be out in force tonight.
You should eat.
I'm not hungry. I'm fine.
I know it's rabbit.
I've been trying
to find some deer,
but there's just none to be had.
It's like they've
all been taken.
I've discovered
we've got a blind spot
in the surveillance.
So, we probably need
another camera.
I'll have
to have a sniff around.
There's a couple of farms...
...out to the west
I've not been through yet.
Come on, kid.
You gotta eat.
I'm fine. I'm not hungry.
Look, I know the boy needs help,
but we're not the ones
to give it to him. All right?
Tomorrow mornin', I'll get him
as close as I can to the camp.
Fine.
Would you stop saying "fine"
when it's not fucking fine?
What is it
that we're doing here, Otto?
We're surviving.
For what exactly?
What are we surviving for?
Your family, they're gone.
Your son is gone.
I'm not your
daughter-in-law anymore.
Do you get that?
I'm just a fucking ghost.
They were infected.
You did the only thing
you could do.
And somehow you
need to find comfort in that.
There's no comfort
in what I did.
I'm gonna go to bed.
-Have you brushed
your teeth yet?
-Yes, Mum.
Well, that's a shame.
I'm gonna have to eat this cake
all by myself.
I haven't. I haven't, Mum.
I promise.
-Are you sure?
-One thousand percent.
Move over.
Good. Because nobody wants to do
that twice on their birthday.
Don't forget... make a wish.
Happy birthday.
Sweetheart, this is really good.
I'm working on the coloring.
-See the blue?
-I do. I love it.
This is going
straight on the fridge.
Hey.
I wished for Dad to come home.
He's helping the sick people.
What's wrong
with the sick people?
I don't know.
It may be a virus.
I wish I could tell you more.
Where did the virus come from?
Stay here. Don't move, okay?
Connor?
Dad? Dad!
Connor, you're scaring us.
Hey.
Oh, easy, easy.
Easy. You're okay.
You're okay.
You're safe. It's all good.
Shh.
Shh!
The door!
Lock it! Lock it!
I can't reach it!
Get down! Get down!
It's gone.
Who are you?
Shouldn't I be asking you
that question?
Are you one of them?
No.
Why are you dressed like them?
Are you okay?
I need to go.
-Where's my backpack?
-You can't leave now.
You'll attract them.
-Where is it?
-Howlers will smell you
from a mile away.
What the fuck have you done
with my backpack?
It's in the house.
It's in there.
Here. It's got salt in it.
Helps with dehydration.
You need to pack it.
-I don't have time.
-Yeah, well, you're gonna
have to find time.
Sit.
You got a name?
Noah.
And yours?
Rory.
Avoided the camps, huh?
For now.
I couldn't believe
how people just...
...obeyed those murdering thugs.
Like no one gave a shit
about freedom no more.
Fear can make you do
a lot of things you shouldn't.
Breathe.
So, how has a runner
got Ivacron?
I broke into camp.
My boy's sick.
Your boy?
He was infected...
...two days ago.
If I don't get
the antidote to him before
the panting starts, then...
What's your son's name?
Leo.
He's eight.
Well, uh, eight and a half,
if you're asking him.
There.
I'm done. You should rest.
I'm grateful
for everything...
...but I have
to get back to my son.
Dawn's a couple of hours away.
Noah.
Noah, I understand
that time's against you,
but if you go out
into that forest,
you're not gonna make it
back to your son.
Fuck!
Okay.
Till dawn.
Then I'm gone.
Got something.
Four heat signatures,
three human, one large animal.
Foot of the ridge.
Come on. Let's go.
We should wait till sunup.
It's too risky moving at night.
If we don't get
the antidote back,
the protection
that our families get is gone.
Your father's
medical benefits...
...gone.
So do you and your old man
wanna chance it out here
on your own?
No?
Can we fucking go now?
That howler was close.
How the fuck did you get inside?
Just wait a minute.
Otto, stop.
How'd he get in our house?
-I let him in.
-You-- you what?
This is becoming a problem, kid.
- Look, he's not GMA.
- No, no, you stay there.
He's got a son
that was infected two days ago,
and he's just trying
to get back to him.
Where's "back"?
Miller's Flat.
"Miller's Flat"?
On the other side of the forest?
It's the truth.
Put the gun down, Otto.
If you so much as flinch
the wrong way, I will kill you.
- We need to get
that jacket off him.
I'll get something of Connor's.
Well, you look like shit.
I feel it.
Look, I don't want
anything from you.
I didn't ask to come here.
All that I want is
to get back to my son.
How did your son get bit?
The dog took off.
Leo ran after her.
You got a dog?
Had.
Well...
I'm sorry about your son.
And your dog.
Here.
I'll do it.
- Aah!
- All right.
Thank you.
Otto.
Let's get him to the table.
What's happening to him?
He's got air build-up
in his chest,
pressuring his lungs,
stopping him breathing.
I'm gonna make a passage
for the air to escape.
- How the fuck
do we do that?
- You can't be serious.
- It's just temporary.
The pressure will build again.
The problem is...
...there are two
major arteries in the chest.
-I have to miss them, or...
-Or what?
Well, he... he'll bleed out.
There it is.
Right...
...there.
Are you sure?
No.
All right, son.
This is gonna hurt.
One...
...two...
...three.
Yeah.
Good.
He just...
...passed out.
That's normal.
It's normal.
I reckon we go
right up the front.
He's been out too long.
Well, you know,
he's lost a lot of blood.
Even if he wakes now...
...he's never gonna make it
to Miller's Flat.
And what about his son?
We've done all we can.
Have we?
I'm getting you out of here
before those agents arrive.
The boy needs it within
72 hours, or it won't work.
You're going up to Callahan's.
They've got a bunker.
You'll be safe there.
I can take the horse.
Rory, you don't even know
what house he's in.
There's, like, five houses
in Miller's Flat.
-You're going up to Callahan's.
-Otto! Listen.
-You're not going
through that forest.
-If I leave now--
Rory, that boy is not Matty.
Isn't he?
What happened to us?
I can't let you go.
I know.
Oh, fuck.
All right. All right,
we got two minutes.
Get him. Get the horse.
Get out of here.
- What about you?
- I'll stall them.
-You can't stay here.
-Rory, I've shot my way out
of worse than this. Go.
Just wait.
That's adrenaline.
You'll know.
Go.
Front's clear.
All right.
The back of the barn. Go.
Go.
Here. I'll saddle her.
What, you're not
gonna let us in?
Well, I got this rule, you see.
Never invite murderers
into the house.
I've been
a real stickler for it.
Right.
You've accidentally
stumbled onto private property.
All land control is
under the new Emergency Act.
GMA owns it now.
Hmm.
I don't remember signing
that document.
But, you know,
the post's been dreadful,
hasn't it?
You should have a look at that.
And you should be in camp.
Well, this was always
the retirement plan.
I think I'm good here.
But thanks for the offer.
Well, I might be willing
to overlook the fact
that you're out here
if you just tell me where he is.
It's just me, chap.
And my beautiful son
and granddaughter,
they're behind you.
Yeah, I saw that.
That's a shame
they weren't in camp.
Well, it's not just the infected
we have to worry about, is it?
We're not interested in you.
All right?
And even if we were,
we're at capacity.
We're hunting a man,
six foot, sandy hair,
probably injured,
definitely hostile.
Have you, uh, seen a man
who fits that description?
Well, you know...
...now I think of it,
there was a fella.
He would have been six foot.
Ah, but you see,
he was bald, and...
...just the one leg.
Oh.
I'm sorry I can't help you
with your inquiries.
Careful.
'Cause without order,
there's only chaos.
Right.
Is that what you told
the millions of imprisoned
with buyer's remorse?
A horse.
Still?
After all this time?
I haven't seen your man.
I'm obliged to tell you that
harboring an enemy of the state
is punishable by death.
I'm obliged to tell you
to fuck off my property.
Aah!
You good?
Yeah, I think so. Fuck.
Logan.
Fuck off.
What'd you say?
Bye.
Logan?
Logan!
-What?
-Two bodies on horseback,
headed for the forest.
-Where's Brooks?
-Dead.
Fuck.
Oh, we gotta move.
I'm not coming with you.
-You know what's at stake.
-I do.
I can't be a part
of this system anymore.
Get on your horse.
No.
Get on your fuckin' horse!
F--
Stop!
You gotta get out of here
before dark.
Noah, wait.
You may never come back.
Her name was Matty.
My husband infected her,
and I didn't protect her.
I put my child in the ground...
...and that guilt eats at you
every minute of every day.
So if I can save you
from doing what I had to,
I'm going into that forest
with you. Okay?
It can't all be for nothing.
Put this on your clothes.
It helps to disguise our scent.
Run!
Down here.
Go through the forest...
...till you get to the river.
What are you doing?
Track it north for two miles.
When you get out...
...keep going
till you reach the valley.
You'll see a house
with a red roof.
Give the antidote to my mother.
She's watching Leo.
You got it?
Yes.
Give me some ammo.
Here.
Go.
Don't stop for anything.
Your daughter...
...was lucky
to have a mother like you.
Now.
Oh, fuck.
Ah, fuck!
Go on, fucking do it.
Where are my boys?
They say God has left us.
Couldn't believe
what we've become.
I know this can't be true.